hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says the equilateral triangle sits in
the center of the semicircle and it
wants to know what is the area of the
square this problem is day seven of our
agvent calendar for the month of
December we're going to solve 31 Katrina
a puzzles in 31 days and I'm doing my
best to keep us on Pace if you want to
try this one on your own pause it right
now because I'm going to solve it in
three two 1 we're trying to find the
area of this orange Square let's label
the sides of the square s and the area
will be equal to s^2 next they're giving
us the diameter of the semicircle is
equal to 6 that means that the radius
would be equal to 3 so if we connect the
center of the semicircle to this corner
of the square that would also be equal
to three and from here let's finish up
this right triangle this side of our
triangle will be equal to S and the base
we don't know yet let's call it X and
now let's solve for x in the given
equilateral triangle the x is this p
right here it's half of the base let's
take this radius and rotate it over here
that means that the height of this
equilateral triangle is equal to three
and if we connect this vertex to this
vertex we have another right triangle
the hypotenuse of our new right triangle
is the same as a side of our equilateral
triangle and since X is half the
distance the whole distance would be 2X
and now we have three sides of a right
triangle let's do Pythagorean theorem
it'll be X 2 + 3^2 is equal to the
quantity 2x^2 3^2 is equal to 9 and this
exponent will distribute to both of
these to give us 2^2 x^2 and 2^2 is
equal to 4 next let's subtract x^2 from
both sides on the left hand side these
will cancel each other out and on the
right hand side 4x^2 - x^2 is 3x^2 next
we can divide both sides by three on the
left hand side 9 / 3 is equal to 3 and
on the right hand side these two threes
will cancel each other out so we're left
with x^2 is equal to 3 next let's square
root both sides on the left hand side
the square root and the square will
cancel each other out and now we've
solved for x x is equal to the < TK of 3
and that is what we were trying to do up
here in the place of this x let's plug
in < tk3 and now let's take this radius
and bring it back over here and we now
have another right triangle let's do
Pythagorean theorem it'll be < tk3 ^2 +
s^2 is equal to 3^2 over here the square
root and the square will cancel each
other out and 3^2 is equal to 9 after we
subtract three from both sides we end up
with s^2 is equal to 9 - 3 which is 6
and S2 is what we were looking for so in
the place of this s squ let's plug in
six this is the area of the orange
Square let's give it a label of unit
squared and put a box around it how
exciting and this is the puzzle for day
eight when I place two three four five
triangles like this what's the
overlapping area can't wait to see
tomorrow's video how exciting